Theresa Hoffmann

UX Researcher

Pittsburgh, PA | theresahoffmann.ux@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/theresahoffmann | resihoff.github.io/portfolio-website

UX Researcher with a background in English literature and PR. Skilled in user research and testing, including surveying, interviewing, and usability testing. Experienced in translating research findings into actionable insights.

SKILLS & TOOLS

User-Centered Design Methodology, User Research, User Personas, User Flows, Card Sorting, Information Architecture, Wireframing, Prototyping, UI Design, UX Writing, Usability Testing, App Design, Web Design, Agile Methodology, Oral and Written Communication

Adobe XD, Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop, Figma, Balsamiq, Marvel, LucidChart, Optimal Workshop, Survey Monkey, Qualtrics, MS Office, Google Workspace, Dropbox, Atom, GitHub, HTML5, CSS3, FigJam, Miro, Trello, Notion

Fluent native speaker of German

UX EXPERIENCE

UX Research Team Co-Lead, Tech Fleet

August 2022 – November 2022

- Built and led the research team of 6 apprentices through generative research, including competitor analysis, secondary
 research, user surveys, and user interviews, to inform The Serious Type's pivot away from being a social platform for teens
 into becoming a production studio helmed by the nonprofit's founder, Nikki Beinstein.
- Synthesized research into user personas, user journey maps, user flows, and a final research report to support the work of the design team in building a mid-fidelity prototype of the new platform.
- Wrote a hand-off document summarizing our team's 8 weeks of work for the Phase 4 team to take over and continue building out and testing the prototype.

UX Research Apprentice, Tech Fleet

May 2022 - July 2022

Created a new, more engaging platform for The Serious Type, a social network for teens to share creative work. Conducted a
competitor analysis, user interviews, user surveys, secondary research, and multiple card sorts to understand the problem
space and better meet users' wants and needs. Designed a progressive web app to replace the current The Serious Type
website based on research insights.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Account Executive, RW Jones Agency

March 2019 - May 2021

- Improved positive media presence of multiple clients while managing various issues faced by those clients. Managed 3 client
 accounts while serving on several other client accounts in support role. Guided clients' internal and external communications
 strategies during the global COVID-19 pandemic and assisted one client with a leadership transition during this crisis.
 Increased positive visibility of clients, including placements in NPR, The Washington Post, The Hill, POLITICO, and other
 national media outlets, and secured additional business from 2 clients.
- Maintained company brand and build the agency's national reputation. Managed production of monthly media planner for clients. Copyedited and produced layout of monthly newsletter for clients. Assisted in managing the RWJ blog, podcast, and website. Produced email marketing campaigns to clients. Elevated the reputation of RWJ and the premier PR agency serving higher education and consistently published content on deadline for my entire tenure.

Account Coordinator, Dick Jones Communications/RW Jones Agency

June 2016 - March 2019

Theresa Hoffmann

UX Researcher

Pittsburgh, PA | theresahoffmann.ux@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/theresahoffmann | resihoff.github.io/portfolio-website

- Supported media relations efforts on behalf of 5-7 clients at any given. Crafted and executed hundreds of national media
 campaigns on behalf of clients, including op-ed writing, national political poll data releases during presidential and mid-term
 elections, and publicizing research and expertise of faculty. Improved national visibility of several clients.
- Crafted a new brand identity for the agency and socialize that identity among existing and prospective clients. Designed logo
 ideas, devised a new color scheme, and selected new fonts. Created all new branded materials, including templates for
 presentations and both client-facing and internal documents. Assisted in the management and rebuild of company website.
 Wrote inbound marketing content. Successfully executed the agency's rebrand without losing clients.

Leasing Agent, Alvern Gardens Apartments, Prudential Realty Company

August 2013 - May 2016

- Improved living conditions on the property by redesigning the checklist for preparing for pest control visits, leading to an increase in evaluations and treatments and reduction in repeat visits from pest control.
- Secured leases of several vacant apartments on a property boasting more than 100 units. Responded to email and phone
 leads as they were received. Gave apartment tours to both scheduled visitors and walk-ins. Processed rental applications,
 payments, and other sensitive documents. Substantially reduced the number of vacancies on the property to the point of
 having a waiting list for the first time in years.
- Redesigned model apartment on a small budget. Took model apartment from a 1980s aesthetic to a universally appealing
 modern, contemporary aesthetic that made rooms feel bigger, brighter, and more open and allowed prospective renters to
 better envision themselves living on the property.

Freelance Writer, University of Pittsburgh at Bradford Communications & Marketing

June 2013 - August 2013

• Contributed content for a special publication celebrating the 50th anniversary of the University of Pittsburgh at Bradford. Contacted alumni, conducted phone interviews with them, wrote and edited articles about their experiences at the institution and their lives since graduating. Successfully produced 7 articles that were printed in the 50th anniversary publication.

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry User Experience Design Certificate (September 2022)

Intensive project-based online training program with a focus on user experience design, user research, user interface design, and frontend development.

Duquesne University, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (May 2016)

Master of Arts in English Literature with a Concentration in Writing and Media Technology

Cook Honors College (CHC) at Indiana University of Pennsylvania (IUP), Indiana, Pennsylvania (May 2013)
Bachelor of Arts in English Writing and Film Studies, Minors in Anthropology and Religious Studies, summa cum laude